A Guide to the Frank Harris Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7453-f
Frank Harris Collection 1919-1929
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7453-f
ca. 30 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase/Gift, 1984 Jul 31
Item Listing
- Manscripts
  - A Rebours by Huysmans reviewed by Frank Harris, [ca. 1926 Dec]; TMs, 2 p.
  - Bound notebook containing notes for "a lecture delivered before the Woodberry Society of Columbia University, New York" entitled "Three Modern Figures: Nietzsche-- Bernard Shaw-- Walt Whitman", AMs, 62 p.
- Letters
  - Frank Harris to Charles Carrington, 1919 Mar 31; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends six sets of
    The Life and Confessions of Oscar Wilde
    . ]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1923 Mar 17; TLS, 1 p.
    [Requests his business address; invites him to visit him at his hotel in Paris; has had his worst cold ever.]
  - Frank A. Groves to Frank Harris, 1924 Jul 24; TLS, 1 p.
    [Requests four copies of first volume of
    [The Life and Confessions of] Oscar Wilde
    and five complete sets; AN by Harris inquires if Groves wants copies of
    My Life and Loves
    computes costs.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1925 Sep 10; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends prospectus for the second volume of [
    ] at a discount; gives him discount for Oscar Wilde book.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1925 Sep 30; TLS, 1 p.
    [Repeats contents of Sep 10 letter; encloses a prospectus; quotes prices for [
    ] and
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1925 Dec 31; ALS, 1 p.
    [Informs him that prices for books remain unchanged; asks that he send check through the American Express Co.; believes that he will complete the third volume of [
    ] by next June.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Jul 9; TLS, 1 p.
    [Gives the prices for
    claims he cannot give discounts on books unless he orders a dozen.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Jul 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Offers to sell him the volumes of
    for a certain price.] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Aug 24; TLS, 1 p.
    [Corrects an error in prices made by his secretary in the July 16 letter; has sent two sets of books; claims the French Government is prosecuting him for the second volume of
    expects this should make it sell better.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Sep 6; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sending four sets of
    that day; cannot sell the books for less than 350 francs because it has been confiscated in England and the United States. ] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Sep 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Received check; unable to send a review of
    A Rebours
    because recent illness has delayed other work, especially third volume of
    . ] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Oct 4; TLS, 1 p.
    [Instructs him to send order for three copies of the first volume of
    to the publisher; has informed the publisher of this situation.] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1926 Dec 13; TLS, 1 p.
    [Informs him that third volume of
    will appear at the end of January; will let him know the precise date; asks him what type of review he wants of
    skeptical that any paper will accept the review.] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1927 Mar 10; TLS, 1 p.
    [Informs him that third installment of
    will be published within eight days; offers to send a copy; quotes prices; refers to perennial trouble of using French postal service.] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1927 Mar 17; TL, 1 p.
    [Makes an argument not to cancel an order for the third installment of
    claims that price is reasonable; believes that French persecution is over; wants to put third installment in wide circulation.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1927 May 3; TL, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for payment; sends him several volumes of
    third and fourth volumes will be published in a single volume in America.] (signed by secretary, A. Krim)
  - Frank Harris to Jean Michaux, 1927 Aug 24; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sends volumes of
    Life and Confessions of Oscar Wilde
    quotes prices; thanks him for check; gives amount still due.] (initialed by Harris and signed by secretary, L. Dowd)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1927 Dec 16; TLS, 1 p.
    [Will sign books when they arrive; demands payment still due; in AN claims payment will be "a welcome Xmas box."] 1 p. (initialed by Harris and signed by secretary, L. Dowd)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, [ca. 1928 Jan]; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for the "tenner"; used it for New Year's gifts.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1928 Mar 13; TLS, 1 p.
    [Gives current account of money he owes; will send him two copies of
    hopes to finish fifth volume of
    by end of month; invites him to lunch or dinner.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1928 Apr 26; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for letters and a check; busy on fifth volume of
    hopes to finish it soon; gives him a list of orders and their prices.]
  - Frank Harris to [ Frank A. Groves], 1928 Apr 27; TLS, 1 p.
    [Has sent five volumes of
    gives current account.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1928 Jul 31; ALS, 3 p.
    [Thanks him for recent order; gives prices for order; requests payment; needs the money for summer holidays; encloses an order form (present).] (in secretary's hand, signed by Harris)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Jan 31; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for order of three copies of
    returned from three month trip to United States; urges him to sell books he has in stock or return them.] (in secretary's hand, signed by Harris)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 May 29; TLS, 1 p.
    [Will supply books on a list at a discount.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Jun 15; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for check; requests remainder of balance so he can use it for holiday.] (secretarial signature)
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Jul 22; ALS, 1 p.
    [Gives travel plans on the French Riviera; asks that he get the copies of
    from Mr. Ritzman of Libriarie Ashe unless he can wait until his return.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Aug 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Requests check for money owed because he needs it.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Aug 28; ALS, 1 p.
    [Sent various volumes of
    and
    requests check.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Oct 14; TLS, 1 p.
    [Sent last of fifteen sets of Oscar Wilde book; thanks him for check.]
  - Frank Harris to Frank A. Groves, 1929 Oct 21; TLS, 1 p.
    [Does not have fifth series of
    Contemporary Portraits
    will get them from America.]